RYAN POPE

rcp3by@virginia.edu | (703) 350-5944 Charlottesville, VA 22903

www.linkedin.com/in/rcpope | github.com/Popestr

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Motivated student and software engineer, completing Computer Science degree. Reliably delivers in fast-paced, goal-driven environments. Able to support team administrative, project coordination, design and programming needs. Experienced in Python and C++, and proficient in Java and JavaScript.

SKILLS

- Programming: Java, Python, C++, Unix, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Matlab
- **Software**: Excel, SolidWorks (CAD/CAM)

 Communication: Public speaking, team management, proofreading and editing, presenting

WORK HISTORY

Project Engineer Intern | Helix Electric - Chantilly, VA

06/2019 - 08/2019

- Double-checked documentation and purchase orders.
- Assisted with Excel spreadsheet creation and management.
- Assisted in organizing site layouts, blueprints, and other various documents.

President & Technician | Reboot For Youth - Great Falls, VA

09/2016 - 09/2018

- Recruited new volunteers and managed weekly meetings.
- Managed the acquisition, refurbishment, and distribution of computing hardware to those in need.
- Spearheaded community outreach campaigns, effectively led a large team, and developed innovative ways to manage operation logistics.

Volunteer | STEMbassadors - Alexandria, VA

09/2016 - 06/2018

- Assisted in planning and delivering numerous activities and special events for STEM clubs and organizations.
- Provided STEM instruction during summer classes in coordination with a given curriculum.

EDUCATION

Thomas Jefferson High School For Science And Technology - Alexandria, VA

06/2018

Advanced Studies Diploma

University of Virginia - Charlottesville, VA

Expected in 05/2022

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

Minor: Business **GPA**: 3.72 / 4.0

RELATED COURSEWORK

Program & Data Representation, Discrete Mathematics, Digital Logic Design, Software Dev. Methods,
Computer Vision, Mobile & Web App Development, Artificial Intelligence